(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 1,
"subtitles": 2
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
本日は、風真いろは2周年ライブにお越しいただきまして、誠にありがとうございます。
Thank you very much for coming to Kazama Iroha's 2nd Anniversary Live today.
本公演をご覧になるにあたっての注意事項を説明いたします。
I will now explain the precautions for viewing this performance.
その1 全力で楽しみ、
Number 1: Enjoy yourself to the fullest,
その2 全力でコメントをし、
Number 2: Comment with all your might,
その3 全力でスクショを撮り、
Number 3: Take screenshots with all your might,
その4 全力でハッシュタグ #風真いろは2周年ライブ でつぶやき、
Number 4: Post with the hashtag #KazamaIroha2ndAnniversaryLive to your heart's content,
その5 全力で幸せな気持ちになっていってください。
Number 5: And please, feel as happy as you possibly can.
それではまもなく開演いたします。
The performance will begin shortly.
風真いろははどこへでも行ける！
Kazama Iroha can go anywhere!
キラキラ光ってるはずなんだ
It's supposed to be shining brightly
ジャッジャッジャ、ファーストビデオオーバー。グッバイバイの毎日だ。
J-J-J, first video over. Every day is a goodbye-bye.
頭こんがらがってバーニングバーニング。
My head is all tangled up, burning burning.
でっかい月の上にお餅があるんだっけ。
Is there mochi on top of the big moon?
宇宙旅行にパスポートは要りますか？
Do I need a passport for space travel?
僕が歩いていく世界の
In the world I'm walking through,
明日はどんな色？
What color will tomorrow be?
君と僕で描いていく二人の色合わさって
The colors we both draw blend together
全然ときめきは全然さ。
My heart doesn't flutter at all, not at all.
会いたい時に会いに行くよ。
I'll go to see you when I want to.
地球の裏から夢の中まで。
From the other side of the Earth into my dreams.
キラキラスカートが揺れる。
The sparkling skirt sways.
エスコート君はエスコート。
Escort, you escort me.
マニュアル通りじゃつまんないでしょ？
Doing things by the book is boring, right?
不安の数だけ希望があるよ。
There's as much hope as there are anxieties.
キラキラ光ってるはずなんだ。
It's supposed to be shining brightly.
冒険しちゃったってありのアイドルが
Even an idol who went on an adventure...
常識もグラついちまってパニックパニック
...makes even common sense shake. Panic, panic!
深海2mのところでマーメイドが恋をしたって
A mermaid fell in love 2 meters deep in the ocean.
嘘か本当か確かめに行きませんか？
Shall we go find out if it's true or false?
僕らの暮らしてる世界は
The world we live in...
一人一人、十人十色
...is made of each person's unique colors.
それもお父さん、お母さんの愛だ色
Those colors are born from parents' love.
愛してるぜベイビー　君は絶品さ
I love you baby, you're exquisite.
雨降り天気でも会いに行くよ
I'll go see you even in rainy weather.
魔法だ　ここまで願えばいいってもんじゃ
It's magic, it's not enough to just wish for it.
いやいや、待ってるわけじゃなくて
No, no, I'm not just waiting around.
デッパチ合わせてハッチャメチャ
It's all chaotic and crazy.
裸足にきっと適わないでしょう
You won't be able to keep up with me barefoot.
無理も通せば道理がなんとやら
Push through the impossible, and reason follows.
パカパカ飛べればいい気がしてるんだ
I feel like it's fine as long as I can keep going.
胸の奥がギュッとなる
My heart tightens.
消えない、消せない、過去笑えるように
So I can laugh at the past I can't erase.
未来が僕らを呼んでる
The future is calling out to us.
ほら踊れる今日は踊っておくのが楽しみグッズ
See, let's dance while we can today!
愛してるぜベイビー　君は絶品さ
I love you baby, you're exquisite.
会いたい時に君に会いに行くよ
I'll go see you whenever I want to.
机の奥から宇宙船まで
From the back of a desk to a spaceship...
フラフラ旅してる途中さ
...I'm in the middle of a wandering journey.
エスコート、君をエスコート
Escort, I'll escort you.
マニュアル通りじゃつまんないでしょう
Doing it by the book is boring, right?
不安の傘を広げ合って、さあ行こう
Let's open our umbrellas of anxiety and go.
パカパカ走ればいい気がしてる
I feel like I just need to keep on running.
キラキラ光ってるはずなんだ
It's supposed to be shining brightly.
ここまで色んな村を旅してきたでござるが
I've traveled to many different villages to get here.
温かい人にね、たくさんの方々に触れて
I've met so many warm and kind people.
世界には色んな人がいるでござるな
There are really all sorts of people in this world.
きっとまだまだ風真の知らないことが
I'm sure there are still many things I don't know.
きっといっぱいあるでござるな
There must be so many of them out there.
あ、特に2つ前の村でいただいた
Oh, especially the ones from the village two stops back.
あの紫色のナスっていう野菜は、誠に誠に美味でござったな
That purple vegetable called 'eggplant' was truly delicious.
またどこかで食べる機会があれば、絶対にたくさん食べよう
If I ever get the chance to eat it again, I'll have a lot.
お、そんなこと言ってる場合じゃない
Oh, this is no time to be talking about that.
さてと、次の村を目指して
Now then, heading towards the next village...
今日も流浪侍は精進あるのみ。目指すは侍ナンバーワンでござる！
I must keep training. I'll be the number one samurai!
まあ風真のこのフィジカルを以てすれば、どんな敵もどんな危険もへっちゃらでござるけど
Well, with my physical skills, no enemy or danger can stop me!
やっぱり心配だなあ
But I'm still a bit worried.
一人で行くのは怖いし
Going all by myself is scary.
あ、そういう時のぽこべぇ！
Oh, that's when I need Pokobe!
ぽこべぇ？
Pokobe?
ぽこべぇ！
Pokobe!
あーもう！またぽこべぇ、はぐれてしまったでござるか？
Oh geez! Did Pokobe get lost again?
え？いないの？
Huh? He's not here?
いなくなっちゃったじゃん。もう！
He's gone. Oh, come on!
今日はお天気の匂いもあり
I can smell the changing weather today...
お天道様も陰ってきちゃったし
...and the sun is starting to hide.
ああ、どこ行ったでござるか...
Oh, where did he go...?
やば、言ってるそばから雨でござるか
Oh no, it's already starting to rain.
全く。おい、ぽこべぇ！
Honestly. Hey, Pokobe!
どこ行ったでござるか！ぽこべぇ！
Where did you go? Pokobe!
ちょっと寒くなってきてし
It's getting a little cold.
もふもふが恋しいでござる
I miss your fluffiness.
ぽこべぇ、どこだよー
Pokobe, where are you?
先の見えない流浪の旅
A wandering journey with no end in sight...
この先、何者になってどう生きればいいんだろうか
What will I become? How should I live my life?
いつか風真も誰かの支えになれる日が来るのだろうか
Will the day come when I can support someone else?
こんな世界を嘆く誰かの
For someone who laments this world...
生きる理由になれるでしょうか
Can I become a reason to live?
これは僕が今君に贈る
This is what I give to you now
最初で最後のアいの言葉だ
My first and last words of love
だれかの心臓になれたなら
If I Could Become Someone's Heart
作詞・作曲 ユリイ・カノン
Lyrics & Composition: Yurii Canon
街も人もゆがみだした
The town and people began to warp
化け物だと気付いたんだ
I realized it was a monster
欲に巣食った愚かさも
The foolishness nested in greed
全てがこの目に映る
Everything is reflected in these eyes
シアトリカルに手の平で
Theatrically, in the palm of a hand
誰も彼も踊らされる
Everyone is being danced around
生まれたんだって知らぬまま
Without knowing they were even born
形骸化した夢は錆び付いてしまった
The skeletal dreams have rusted away
「アイをください」
"Please give me love"
きっと誰もが願った
Surely everyone wished for it
「アイをください」
"Please give me love"
そっと震えた手を取って
Gently taking the trembling hand
心抉る
Gouging the heart
こんな世界と嘆く誰かの
Someone lamenting such a world
生きる理由になれるでしょうか
Can I become a reason to live?
いつか終わると気付いた日から
From the day I realized it would end someday
死へと秒を刻む心臓だ
The heart ticks the seconds toward death
ねぇ、このまま雨に溺れて
Hey, drowning in the rain like this
藍に溶けたって構わないから
I don't mind melting into the indigo
どうか、どうか、また明日の方を
Please, please, toward tomorrow again
傘を差し出して待っていてよ
Hold out an umbrella and wait
もしも夢が覚めなければ
If I never woke from the dream
姿を変えずにいられたか
Could I have stayed the same?
解けた指から消える温度
The warmth disappearing from loosened fingers
血を巡らせるのは誰の思い出
Whose memories make the blood circulate?
雨に濡れた配線 朽ちた病棟 並んだ送電塔
Rain-soaked wiring, decayed wards, transmission towers
夕暮れのバス停 止まったままの観覧車
Sunset bus stop, a Ferris wheel that has stopped
机に咲く花 君の声も 何もかも
Flowers on a desk, your voice, everything
最初からなかったみたい
As if they never existed from the start
死にたい僕は今日も息をして
I, who want to die, am still breathing today
生きたい君は明日を見失って
You, who want to live, have lost tomorrow
なのにどうして悲しいのだろう
Yet why is it so sad?
いずれ死するのみが人間だ
Only dying eventually is what it means to be human
あぁ、永遠なんてないけれど
Ah, there's no such thing as eternity
思い通りの日々じゃないけれど
The days aren't exactly as I'd like them to be
脆く弱い人に繋がれた
Connected to fragile and weak people
次の夜明けがまた訪れる
The next dawn will come again
どんな世界も君がいるなら
In any world, if you are there
生きていたいと思えたんだよ
I felt like I wanted to keep living
僕の地獄で君はいつでも
In my hell, you are always
絶えず鼓動する心臓だ
A heart that beats without ceasing
愛しき書き残したように
Someday, I wrote to you...
僕もだれかの心臓になれたんだな
I, too, was able to become someone's heart
風真は…
Kazama...
…だれかの…
...someone's...
あ！ ぽこべぇ！
Ah! Pokobe!
よかった…無事でござるか？
I'm so glad... Are you safe?
もう本当に探したんですよ。
I was really looking for you.
無事ですか？
Are you okay?
よかった…
Thank goodness...
ねぇ、ぽこべぇ。
Hey, Pokobe.
風真、だれかのためになれるかな？
Can I... become helpful to someone?
え？ なに？ なに？
Eh? What? What is it?
あ、外の世界には風真を必要とする仲間が必ずいる？
Oh, in the outside world, there are definitely comrades who need me?
本当に？
Really?
そうでござるか。
Is that so.
うん、なに？
Yeah, what?
あ、それにまだ外の世界にはたくさんの面白い未知のことも待ってる？
Ah, and there are still many interesting unknown things waiting in the outside world?
確かにそうかもしれないでござるな。
That might indeed be true.
確かに、そんな気がしてきた。
Indeed, I'm starting to feel that way.
ぽこべぇ、ありがとうでござる。
Pokobe, thank you.
も！
Oh!
そんな話してたら見て！
While we were talking, look!
雨も止んだ！ 晴れてきたでござる！
The rain has stopped! It's cleared up!
まだまだ知らないこといっぱいあるから
There are still many things I don't know,
見に行かなきゃいけないでござるよな
so I have to go see them, right?
よし！
Alright!
まだまだね、知らないこと一緒に探しに行くでござる！
Let's go find more things we don't know together!
まだ見ぬ仲間を探しに
To find friends we haven't met yet,
ともに歩んでいくでござる！
let's walk forward together!
ラプ殿へ
To Lap-dono,
いつもはすぐ煽ったりバカにするけど
I usually tease or make fun of you right away,
今日だけは特別に言います。
but just for today, I'll say this specially.
人見知りだったかざまに
To Kazama, who was shy,
明るく、気兼ねなく接して話しかけてくれて、ありがとう。
thank you for being cheerful and talking to me without hesitation.
ラプ殿と出会って友達になれて
Meeting Lap-dono and becoming friends...
本当によかった。
...was truly wonderful.
ホロックスの総帥がラプ殿でよかった。
I'm glad the leader of HoloX is Lap-dono.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
大好きだよ。
I love you.
何回言ってもピク耳持たない
No matter how many times I say it, you don't listen at all
お勉強アウトサイダー
A study outsider
どうか全力疾走この指とまりなさい
Please, full speed ahead, follow my lead
だから止まりなさい
So stop right there
うるさいんだよ 急いでんだよ
You're noisy! I'm in a hurry!
わざわざ暇なんですか？
Are you that bored?
誰もいないしこれくらい良いだろう
There's no one else, so this much should be fine
君に構う暇はないから
I don't have time to deal with you
じゃあね
See ya
ねえねえ聞いてんの？
Hey, hey, are you listening?
風を乱してんの
You're disturbing the air
はいはいもう分かりました
Yeah, yeah, I get it already
聞く気はないけどね
Though I have no intention of listening
やっぱお前なんか めっちゃ嫌いだ！
As I thought, I really hate you!
怒っちゃってんの？ お顔見ろ
Are you angry? Look at your face
やっぱ絶対的に俺の方が上って言って競ってまたゲラゲラ
As I thought, absolutely I'm the superior one, and we compete and laugh again
いったい何のためになるのやら
I wonder what this is even for
不謹慎真面目ヤクザ
Imprudent, serious yakuza
少しルール破ったくらいでキレすぎだろ
You're overreacting just for breaking a few rules
本当にしつこいわ
Seriously, you're persistent
あーほらまたやってる
Ah, look, you're doing it again
また破ってる
Breaking them again
学習してないようで
It seems you haven't learned
シャツも出てるわネクタイ緩いまで 親の顔が見てみたいもんですな
Your shirt's out and your tie's loose too, I'd like to see your parents' faces
あーそうですか 今度したら絶対許しません
Ah, is that so? If you do it next time, I definitely won't forgive you
やっぱお前なんか めっちゃ嫌いだ！
As I thought, I really hate you!
怒っちゃってるの笑顔は隠せない
You're angry but you can't hide your smile
やっぱ絶対に仲良くとかしないって言って睨んでまたゲラゲラ
As I thought, absolutely we won't get along, and we glare and laugh again
ねえちょっと捕まえてごらんなさい
Hey, try and catch me
バカはほらハシになって 何回言えば
Stupid people are like ladders, how many times must I say it
なあどうした優等生 負けを認めますか？
Hey, what's wrong, honor student? Do you admit defeat?
どうやら全く反省してないようですな
It seems you haven't reflected at all
ねえねえ聞いてんの？
Hey, hey, are you listening?
頭に血でものぼっちゃってんの
Has the blood rushed to your head?
はいはいもう分かりました
Yeah, yeah, I get it already
もうブチ切れちゃうからね
I'm about to snap, you know
ありたけ全部巻き込んでドタバタ
Throwing everything in, making a scene
破壊的天候でめちゃくちゃ
Messy with destructive weather
もう一切のものは見ずに火花散って戦うのだ
Don't look at anything else, just sparks flying in battle
お前なんかめっちゃ嫌いだ！
I really hate you!
この先もずっとずっとずっと嫌いだ！
I'll keep on hating you forever and ever and ever!
やっぱ全然食らってなかったのにって言って5秒後にはメラメラ
As I thought, even though I said it didn't affect me at all, 5 seconds later I'm burning up
ルイ姉へ
To Lui-nee,
かざまが元気ない時、いつも外に連れ出してくれるルイ姉。
Lui-nee, you always take Kazama out when I'm feeling down.
よく周りを見ていて、頼りになって、でもおちゃめで可愛い所もあって、
You're always looking out for others, you're reliable, but you also have a playful and cute side.
そんなルイ姉と過ごす時間が、かざまにとって癒しの時間でした。
The time spent with such a Lui-nee was a healing time for Kazama.
本当にありがとう。
Thank you so much.
「ルイ姉のいろはなら大丈夫」っていう言葉のおかげで、今日も頑張れてます。
Thanks to your words, "Lui-nee's Iroha will be fine," I can do my best today too.
ルイ姉大好き。
I love you, Lui-nee.
また一緒にお出かけしようね！
Let's go out together again!
右肩に紫蝶
Purple butterfly on the right shoulder
キスをしたこの部屋の隅で
Kissed in the corner of this room
切ないという感情を知る
Learning the emotion called sadness
響くピアノ 不協和音
Resonating piano, dissonance
右肩に紫蝶
Purple butterfly on the right shoulder
キスをしたこの部屋の隅で
Kissed in the corner of this room
この部屋の隅で
In the corner of this room,
切ないと云う感情を知る
I learn the emotion called sorrow.
響くピアノ　不協和音
The resonating piano, a discordance.
悪い夢にうなされた私を
Me, who was plagued by a bad dream,
早く起こして
please wake me up quickly.
どんなことでも始まれば
No matter what, once it starts,
終わるのが道理でしょう
it's only natural that it will end, right?
どこかいいかなんて
If you ask me where is a good place,
聞かれても困る きれいな
I'll be troubled. Beautiful...
夜に惑わされた
led astray by the night,
眩ゆい光を まといながら
while wearing the dazzling light.
長いまつげ三日月アイライン
Long eyelashes, crescent moon eyeliner,
まぶたにのせて光るリップ
glittering lip color on my eyelids.
右肩に紫蝶々
A purple butterfly on the right shoulder.
キスをしたこの部屋の隅で
Kissed in the corner of this room,
切ないと云う感情を知る
I learn the emotion called sorrow.
響くピアノ不協和音
The resonating piano, a discordance.
雨の中で濡れた
My hair wet in the rain
髪が異常に冷たくて
is unusually cold.
寂しさをトイレに
Vomiting my loneliness
吐き出して震えて待って
into the toilet, and waiting while shivering.
追いかけては逃げるから
Because it runs away when chased,
それ以上で返して
return it with even more than that.
真剣だから笑う
I laugh because I'm serious.
痛い目に合うよ　いい？
You'll have a painful experience, okay?
赤い爪と安物の指輪
Red nails and a cheap ring,
傷つく度増えるピアス
the piercings increase each time I'm hurt.
抱き寄せて　歪んだ身体
Hold me close, my distorted body,
埋めるのは貴方しかいない
the only one who can fill it is you.
そうでしょう？わかってるくせに
Isn't that right? Even though you know.
境界線とっくに越えてる
I've long since crossed the boundary line.
後悔は死ぬほどしてる
I regret it to death,
その分だけ快感を呼び覚ます
and just as much, I awaken the pleasure.
狂い出した私を止めて
Stop me, who has begun to go mad,
一瞬で楽にしてよ
and put me at ease in an instant.
傷口から溶け出したものは愛情それとも...
What melted out from the wound, was it love or...
後悔は死ぬほどしてる
I regret it to death,
その分だけ快感を呼び覚ます
and just as much, I awaken the pleasure.
狂い出した私を止めて
Stop me, who has begun to go mad,
一瞬で楽にしてよ
and put me at ease in an instant.
抱き寄せて　歪んだ身体
Hold me close, my distorted body,
埋めるのは貴方しかいない
the only one who can fill it is you.
そうでしょう？わかってるくせに
Isn't that right? Even though you know.
境界線とっくに越えてる
I've long since crossed the boundary line.
右肩に紫蝶々
A purple butterfly on the right shoulder.
キスをしたこの部屋の隅で
Kissed in the corner of this room,
切ないと云う感情を知る
I learn the emotion called sorrow.
響くピアノ不協和音
The resonating piano, a discordance.
右肩に紫蝶々
A purple butterfly on the right shoulder.
キスをしたこの部屋の隅で
Kissed in the corner of this room,
切ないと云う感情を知る
I learn the emotion called sorrow.
響くピアノ不協和音
The resonating piano, a discordance.
こよちゃんへ
To Koyo-chan,
いつも元気でがんばり屋さん。
you're always energetic and such a hard worker.
こよちゃんはかざまにとって正直あこがれでした。
To be honest, Kazama has always looked up to you.
がんばる姿に元気をもらってます。
I get energy from seeing you work so hard.
一昨日もポストで緊張してるかざまにエールをありがとう。
Thank you for the encouragement on your post when Kazama was nervous the other day.
いつも引っ張ってくれて優しくて頼りになるこよちゃんが
Koyo-chan, who is always leading the way and is so kind and reliable,
かざまに相談ごとをしてくれたとき
when you came to Kazama for advice,
すごくすごく嬉しかったです。
it made me very, very happy.
またいつでも頼ってね。
Please rely on me again anytime.
いつもありがとう。大好きだよ。
Thank you for everything. I love you.
Ready?
あの日忘れた夢色落としモノはたまごみたい
The dream-colored lost item forgotten that day is like an egg.
煌めく空をなぞったら
If I trace the sparkling sky
ほんのちょっと楽しくなるね
It gets just a little bit more fun
だから
So
そっと手を広げましょ
Let's gently spread our hands
ほら描こうよ
Look, let's draw
キャラメル・キャンディ・チョコレート
Caramel, candy, chocolate
お洒落でカワイイティータイムは
A fashionable and cute teatime
ちょっとお疲れちゃいそうだし
Seems like it might be a bit tiring
アゲアゲで行こうや
So let's go with high spirits!
アゲアゲ！
High spirits!
今日は楽しんで楽しもう
Let's have fun and enjoy today
もちろんなんでもありで当然でしょ
Of course, anything goes, that's natural right?
手ぇ振りかぶるくらいがストライク
Swinging your arms big is a strike
完璧になれちゃうね
We can become perfect
尋常じゃ出来ないよな
We can't do it normally
忘れないで君のBGM
Don't forget your BGM
甘い匂いに釣られたのなら
If you're lured by the sweet scent
それじゃみんな
Then everyone
宴の幕開けだ！
It's the start of the banquet!
Poppin' Candy Fever!
弾けちゃえフレーバー
Let the flavor pop out
Party Party なんです Shall we dance?
It's a party party, shall we dance?
なんてったってフィーバー
Because it's a fever after all
ウサギもトラも
Rabbits and tigers too
ワッショイワッショイ踊りあかそう
Wasshoi wasshoi, let's dance the night away
あぽりやんよん
Aporiyan yon
Poppin' Candy How?
招いてよドリーマー
Invite us, dreamer
Check it Check it なんです Shall we dance?
It's a check it check it, shall we dance?
なんてったってフィーバー
Because it's a fever after all
テンションはアツくて
The tension is hot
もっともっと溶けちゃうくらい
So much that we might melt more and more
いーせーのー
One, two...
歌え！ チャチャチャ！
Sing! Cha-cha-cha!
笑え！ イェーイェー！
Laugh! Yeah-yeah!
讃え！ ワッホイ！
Praise! Wahhoi!
さあ、もう1回！ チャチャチャ！
Now, one more time! Cha-cha-cha!
もう1回！ イェーイェー！
One more time! Yeah-yeah!
もう1回！ ワッホイ！
One more time! Wahhoi!
さあ、ハイ、どうぞ！
Now, here you go!
クロエへ
To Chloe
つらい時、つらいと言えないござるに
When times were tough and I couldn't say it was hard
気がついて声をかけてくれたのは、クロエでした。
the one who noticed and reached out to me was Chloe.
あの時話しかけてくれた事、本当にうれしかったです。
The fact that you spoke to me then really made me happy.
いつも話を聞いてくれて、話を聞かせてくれて、ありがとう。
Thank you for always listening to me and sharing your stories with me.
あの周年の告知ポストの真似も、実は結構うれしかったです。
To be honest, I was also quite happy when you imitated my anniversary announcement post.
優しくて努力家なクロエが、ござるは大好きです。いろはより。
I love you, Chloe, for being so kind and hardworking. From Iroha.
なあ元気？
Hey, how are you?
調子はどうだい？
How's it going?
ああ、もうね、そういうのやめたんだ
Ah, you know, I stopped doing that kind of thing
なんか、もう回復の見込みは無い
Like, there's no hope of recovery anymore
そうなんだ
I see
何も聞かないでくれ
Please don't ask me anything
傲慢　ねぶみ　断罪
Arrogance, appraisal, condemnation
悔悟　越境　共有もソレダドー
Repentance, crossing borders, sharing is also like that...
はい、そうです　正真正銘僕のせいだった
Yes, that's right, it was genuinely my fault
よくある話
A common story
単純明快　読み物にしたくて
Simple and clear, wanting to turn it into something to read
描くべきという理想を殺して
Killing the ideal of what should be drawn
もう散々だって逃げる勇気もない
I've had enough, but I don't even have the courage to run away
早くもっと落ちて
Hurry and fall further
生きていたいよ
I want to live
毎夜　眼を塞ぐ透明の不快を
Every night, the transparent discomfort that shuts my eyes
灰を蝕む実在を
The existence that erodes the ashes
理不尽も　孤独も　喰らって行け
Eat up the absurdity and the loneliness
それらすべて意味はないんだ
None of it means anything at all
僕らは生きるしかないんだ
We have no choice but to live
本当にさ
Really
おい お前 そっちはどうだい
Hey, you, how's it going over there?
あー まだ そんなことやってんだ
Ah, still doing that kind of thing?
そう いや 付き合ってた子とは
So, by the way, with the person you were dating
どうなったんだ?
What happened?
何も言わないでくれ
Don't say anything
笑えない大層な敗北感
A grand sense of defeat that I can't laugh at
終わりまで連れ回さないで
Don't drag me along until the end
はい 今日は大変身に染みるお話でした
Yes, today was a story that really hit home
満たされたかい?
Are you satisfied now?
真っ黒に濁って割れた心も
Even my heart, clouded pitch-black and cracked
アルコールで消毒して眠る
I'll disinfect with alcohol and go to sleep
もう 痣だらけいい鴨 見世物になって
Already full of bruises, a perfect target on display
もっと もっと 落ちて
Falling deeper and deeper
生きていたいよ
I want to live
真夜中を掴む空気も未来も
The air that grips the midnight, and the future too
内臓を飾る肉塊も
Even the mass of flesh that adorns my organs
幸せも不幸も疑わなくていい
I don't need to doubt happiness or misfortune
それらすべて変わらないんだ
None of it will ever change
僕らは知らなくていいんだ
We don't need to know
生きていたいよ
I want to live
なんでか分からないけど
I don't know why, though
生きていたいよ
I want to live
DNAという聖書
The bible called DNA
絶望も恐怖も恨まなくていい
I don't need to resent despair or fear
どうせ何も変わらないんだ
Nothing's going to change anyway
生きていたいよ
I want to live
何の希望もないけど
Even though there's no hope
生きていたいよ
I want to live
本能は赤く脈打つの
My instincts pulse red
生きていたいよ 生きてたたたいよ
I want to live, I wa-wa-want to live
本当に残念だけど
It's truly a shame, but
僕らは生きるしかないんだ
We have no choice but to live
騙してごめんよ
Sorry for deceiving you
言えなくてごめんよ
Sorry for not being able to say it
見えなくてごめんよ
Sorry for not being able to see it
そして本当に悲しいけれど
And although it's truly sad
苦しいだけが絆なんだ
Pain alone is what binds us
外へ出ていった通り
Just as I went outside...
外の世界には、風真の知らないことがいっぱいあった。
...there were so many things in the outside world that I didn't know about.
そこで出会えた仲間たち。
The friends I met there.
やっと見つけた大切な場所。
The precious place I finally found.
ぷろろーぐさむらい、風真いろはから。
From the "prologue samurai," Kazama Iroha...
秘密結社holoxの用心棒、風真いろはへ。
...to the bodyguard of Secret Society holoX, Kazama Iroha.
飛び込んでいこう、僕らのセカイへ！
Let's dive in, to our world!
セカイ
作詞 DECO*27 作曲 堀江晶太(kemu) 編曲 Rockwell
Sekai
Lyrics: DECO*27 / Composition: Syouta Horie (kemu) / Arrangement: Rockwell
ずっと探してたんだよ
I've been looking for it all this time
特別だって言える場所
A place I can call special
なんで僕を選んだの?
Why did you choose me?
笑うキミが手を引いたんだ
While laughing, you took my hand
だってキミはすごいから
Because you are so amazing
負けらんないなって思うんだよ
I feel like I can't afford to lose
どんな時も僕の中に
No matter when, inside of me
キミの声が鳴り響いていた
Your voice was echoing
怖いんだ
I'm scared
何もない僕だけどできるかな
I have nothing, but I wonder if I can do it
自信のなさと しょうもなさで 一勝負さ
With my lack of confidence and worthlessness, I'll give it a shot
けどキミは「それがどうしたの?」って顔をして
But you look at me as if to say, "So what?"
歌を歌うじゃない それはズルいじゃない?
And you sing a song... isn't that cheating?
飛び込んでいこう 僕らのセカイへ
Let's dive in, to our world
正解の想いに出会えるかな
I wonder if I can find the right feelings
歌っていたい
I want to keep singing
踊っていたい
I want to keep dancing
痛いくらい笑えるように
So that I can smile until it hurts
名前もない僕らの世界を
Our world that doesn't even have a name
迷っていけるよ キミとだから
I can find my way through, because I'm with you
変わっていこう 願うように
Let's change, just as we wish
今僕ら 期待の未体験を
Now, let's take on the untried experience we expect
キミの未来を僕が歌うよ
I will sing of your future
描いてもっと Yeah
Draw more, yeah
泣いてもいいじゃん それも答えだ
It's okay to cry, that's an answer too
どうしたっていいよ
Anything is fine
思いは全部 零さないように 抱きしめながら
Embracing all my feelings so as not to spill them
キミと見たいセカイへ
To the world I want to see with you
ずっと探してたんだよ
I've been searching for it for a long time
特別だって言える場所
A place I can call special
どんな僕になるんだろう
I wonder what kind of person I'll become
踊るココロ変えないように
Trying not to change this dancing heart
ちょっとだけその先で
Just a little further ahead
また笑えるよ
I'll be able to smile again
もらったバトンは勇気に
The baton I received turns into courage
ありがとうは歌声に
My gratitude turns into a singing voice
気付いたんだ 僕にしか出来ないこともあること
I realized there are things only I can do
誰かのとこへ ちゃんと歌を届けたいのさ
I want to deliver my song properly to someone
ほら 怖くて震える手でビート刻めば
Look, if I strike a beat with my trembling, fearful hands
夢も近いじゃない？ 僕らひとりじゃない
Isn't the dream close? We aren't alone
飛び込んでいこう 僕らのセカイへ
Let's dive in, into our world
正解の想いに出会えるかな
I wonder if I can encounter the right feelings
歌っていたい 踊っていたい
I want to keep singing, I want to keep dancing
痛いくらい笑えるように
So that I can smile until it hurts
名前もない僕らの世界を
Our nameless world
迷っていけるよ キミとだから
I can wander through it, because it's with you
変わっていこう 願うように
Let's keep changing, just as we wished
今僕ら期待の未体験を
Now, we face the unexpected experiences we hoped for
飛び込んでいこう 僕らのセカイへ
Let's dive in, into our world
正解の想いに出会えるかな
I wonder if I can encounter the right feelings
歌っていたい 踊っていたい
I want to keep singing, I want to keep dancing
痛いくらい笑えるように
So that I can smile until it hurts
名前もない僕らの世界を
Our nameless world
迷っていけるよ キミとだから
I can wander through it, because it's with you
変わっていこう 願うように
Let's keep changing, just as we wished
今僕ら期待の未体験を
Now, we face the unexpected experiences we hoped for
キミの未来を僕が歌うよ 描いてももっと Yeah
I'll sing of your future, keep drawing more, yeah
泣いてもいいじゃん それも答えだ どうしたっていいよ
It's okay to cry, that's also an answer, anything is fine
想いは全部 零さぬように抱きしめながら
Embracing all my feelings so that none are spilled
キミと見たいセカイへ
To the world I want to see with you
はい！
Yes!
皆様、こんばんはでござる！ここまでの「風真いろは物語」、いかがだったでしょうか？
Everyone, good evening! How was the "Kazama Iroha Story" so far?
ただの侍から、色んな大切な仲間に出会い、ホロライブという世界にやってきて、holoXの風真いろはになりました！
From just a samurai, I met many precious companions, came to this world called Hololive, and became holoX's Kazama Iroha!
わーい！でござる！…締まらないけど。
Yay! ...That didn't sound very cool, though.
というわけでですね、ここまで色んな道を歩んできましたが、風真いろはがホロライブに入る前の「IFストーリー」ということで、やらせていただきました。ありがとうございました！
So, I've walked many paths to get here, and I performed this as an "IF story" of what if Kazama Iroha hadn't joined Hololive. Thank you very much!
そして嬉しいことに、今Xのトレンドで、この「#風真いろは2周年LIVE」これ、1位になってるみたいです！本当にありがとうございます！大変恐縮です！
And happily, on X's trends right now, this "#KazamaIroha2ndAnniversaryLIVE" seems to be at number 1! Thank you so much! I'm truly honored!
はい、ということでですね、色々あるんですけど、今回はその物語に沿って、今回ステージも作っていただきました。かっこいい！
Yes, so, there's a lot, but this time a stage was created specifically following that story. So cool!
演劇っぽい、このステージになっております。また詳しいお話はですね、ま、後日アフタートークさせていただければなと思います。
It's like a theatrical stage. I'll talk more about the details in a later after-talk.
そして、そして。ここまでですね、ちょっと不慣れだったんですけど、holoXに対しての手紙と一緒に歌と踊りをやらせていただきました。
And, and. Up to here, although I'm a bit inexperienced, I performed singing and dancing along with a letter to holoX.
なんとこちらのholoXとのコラボ、後ろでMVが流れていましたね。そう、そういうことなんです。
Surprisingly, for this collaboration with holoX, an MV was playing in the background. Yes, that's what it means.
現在、こちらの曲たち4曲ですね、鋭意制作中でございます！でき次第投稿するので、皆様ね、楽しみにしててくださーい！
Currently, these 4 songs are under intensive production! They'll be posted as soon as they're ready, so please look forward to them, everyone!
ちょっとね、お水休憩して、まだまだダンスするから、ちょっとあとチャキ丸と羽織置いてくるわ。暑すぎでござる！
I'll take a quick water break, since I'll be dancing more, and I'll go put down Chakimaru and my haori. It's too hot!
暑い…本当に暑い。暑いって。
Hot... it's really hot. I'm telling you, it's hot.
はい、本当に暑い。ふぅ、ただいま皆様。戻ってきたでござる。ふぅ。
Yes, it's really hot. Whew, I'm back, everyone. I've returned. Whew.
それじゃあですね、皆様。今風真いろはがholoXの風真いろはになったところで、今日は2周年ライブということで、ライブなので、やっぱりアイドルらしく、この後もガンガン盛り上げていきますよー！
Well then, everyone. Now that Kazama Iroha has become holoX's Kazama Iroha, since today is a 2nd-anniversary live, and since it's a live, I'll keep things exciting from here on out, just like an idol!
それじゃあ皆さん準備はいいですか？
Alright everyone, are you ready?
次の曲行きます！
Going to the next song!
次の曲は、ヒロイン育成計画！
The next song is, Heroine Training Program!
きっとヒロインなら綺麗で
If I were a heroine, I'd be beautiful
王子様にチヤホヤされるでしょ
And pampered by a prince, right?
芋女の私も
Even a plain girl like me
お姫様になれたらなんてね
Could become a princess... just kidding!
イェイ！
Yay!
ヒロイン育成計画
Heroine Training Program
作詞 shito / Gom 作曲 shito
Lyrics: shito / Gom, Composition: shito
バイト探し
Looking for a part-time job
採用なし
No one's hiring
やけになって飛び込む
I desperately dive in
場違いすぎる世界
Into a world where I don't belong
パシリばかり
Always running errands
雑用係
A mere chore person
最悪な奴待望
Looking forward to the worst guy
マネージャー就任です
I've become the manager
バレたのさ　い・ご・こ・ち
It's been found out... my comfor-ta-bi-li-ty
妬まれるのやだし
I hate being envied
生きるためだし
It's just to make a living
きっとヒロインなら綺麗で
If I were a heroine, I'd be beautiful
王子様にチヤホヤされるでしょ
And pampered by a prince, right?
芋女の私も
Even a plain girl like me
お姫様になれたらなんてね
Could become a princess... just kidding!
私をプロデュースして
Please produce me
髪も服も全部可愛くして
Make my hair and clothes all cute
いつか出会う王子様
The prince I'll meet someday
どこで何をしてるの？神様
Where and what is he doing? Oh God
待ってますから気長に
I'll be waiting patiently
はい！
Hi!
ある日出会う
One day I meet
運命の人
My destined person
紳士な振る舞いに
His gentlemanly behavior
ドキドキしちゃったんだ
Made my heart skip a beat
名前なんて
Asking for a name
聞けるはずない
I could never do that
また会いたいななんて
Wishing I could see him again
願ってるだけでした
I was just wishing
時が止まる　また会えたね君に
Time stands still, I've met you again
やっぱり怖いや
It's still scary, though
きっと少女漫画じゃ両思い
In girls' manga, it'd surely be mutual love
ベタでいいじゃんむしろベタがいいじゃん
The cliché is fine, I'd rather have it
モブ女の私も
Even a background girl like me
ヒロインなる気ありますなんてね
Has the will to be a heroine... just kidding!
すぐにくっつけばいい
I wish we could just hit it off
悲劇いらないシェイクスピア
No need for a Shakespearean tragedy
やっと会えた王子様
Finally I've met the prince
まずは名前教えてそうですもんね
First, please tell me your name, that's how it goes
ヒロインらしく自然に
Naturally, like a heroine
バレちゃった最悪もやしつらに
It was found out... my worst look
これじゃダメだ100点振られるって
This is no good, I'll be 100% rejected
どうすればいいの
What should I do?
気持ちなら負けないなんてみんな同じこと思ってて
Saying my feelings won't lose... everyone thinks the same
そこからの勇気と推しが大事なんです聞いて
From there, courage and 'oshi' are important, listen!
きっとヒロインなら綺麗で
If I were a heroine, I'd be beautiful
王子様にチヤホヤされるでしょ
And pampered by a prince, right?
芋女の私も
Even a plain girl like me
お姫様になれるのなんてね
Could I become a princess? Just kidding!
自信ちょっとついたよ
I've gained a bit of confidence
当たって砕けたら
If I go for it and fail
馬鹿にして笑ってよお願い
Please make fun of me and laugh, I beg you
行ってきますね告白
I'm off to confess my love
ヒロインになれ今日から
Become a heroine from today
作詞 DECO*27 作曲 sasakure.UK
Lyrics: DECO*27, Composition: sasakure.UK
初めましてとか
Saying 'nice to meet you'
何回言ったっけ
How many times did I say that?
私本当は人見知りで
I'm actually quite shy
ドキドキしてるよ実はいまだって
My heart is pounding, to tell you the truth, even now
うまく歌えてるかな怖いんだいまでも
Am I singing well? I'm still scared
それでも伝えたいだからきっと頑張れるんだって
Still, I want to tell you, so I'm sure I can do my best
逃げないんだ
I won't run away
君に出会って
Meeting you
みんな出会って
Meeting everyone
私出会って
Meeting 'me'
よかったよ
I'm so glad
何回言ったって足りないよ
No matter how many times I say it, it's not enough
声に出してサンキュー
Saying it out loud, 'Thank you'
あれなんだか
Wait, somehow
私の名前みたい
It sounds like my name
今日もありがとう
Thank you again today
「はじめまして」とか何回言ったっけ
How many times did I say "Nice to meet you"?
私 本当に嬉しかったんだ
I was truly happy.
わくわくしてるよ これからもずっと
I'm excited, now and forever.
広がっていくんだ 繋がっていけるんだ
It's spreading out, we're being connected.
弾ける音粒 描いてく筆先
Bouncing sound droplets, a brush tip that draws.
奏でて音を 生まれてく輪の中で
Playing sounds within the circle that's being born.
泣きたくなること たくさんあったよ
There were many times I wanted to cry.
でも笑ってばかりだったら ごめんね ありがとう
But if I was always just laughing, I'm sorry. Thank you.
幸せだよ お返しするよ
I'm happy. I'll give back to you.
プレゼント 私だけ
Because I don't like just being
もらってばかりじゃ 嫌だから
on the receiving end of gifts.
受け取ってもらわなきゃ困る この歌を
You have to accept it, or I'll be in trouble... this song.
君に出会って みんな出会って 私出会って よかったよ
I'm glad I met you, met everyone, and met myself.
何回言ったって 足りないよ
No matter how many times I say it, it's not enough.
声に出して サンキュウ
Out loud: Thank you.
あれ なんだか 私の名前みたい
Wait, it's somehow like my name.
今日も そして明日だって この先だって
Today, and tomorrow, and from now on as well.
私はずっと ここにいる
I'll always be here.
何かあったら 会いに来てよ 歌うよ 何度だって
If anything happens, come see me. I'll sing, any number of times.
「はじめまして」も「また明日」も「久しぶり」も みんなありがとう イェイ
"Nice to meet you," "See you tomorrow," "Long time no see"... thank you everyone, yay!
はい！はい、はい、はい！
Yes! Yes, yes, yes!
一回水飲んでいい？
Can I have a drink of water for a second?
水飲ませて... すー、はー。
Let me drink some water... (Breathing).
危ない。続いて二曲連続歌わせていただきました。
That was close. Following that, I sang two songs in a row.
はい、いかがだったでしょうか？
So, how was it?
ね、アイドルになったんで、ヒロイン育成計画と
You know, since I've become an idol, I sang "Heroine Training Plan" and...
そして皆さんにね、ありがとうの気持ちを込めて、サンキュウを歌わせていただきました。
...and with my feelings of gratitude for everyone, I sang "Thank You."
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
やばい！喋らなきゃいけないことがこれからいっぱいあるんですけども
Oh boy! There's a lot of things I have to talk about now...
っていうことは皆さん何が来るかわかりますね？
...which means you all know what's coming, right?
そうです！これから怒涛の告知タイムです！イェイ！
That's right! It's time for a surge of announcements! Yay!
ちょっとお付き合いくださいね、お願いしますね。
Please stay with me for a bit, okay?
それではですね、まずいっぱいあるんですけど、一つ目から！
Well then, there are many, but let's start with the first one!
まず、風真いろは、今回もグッズが出ます！こちらどーん！
First, Kazama Iroha is releasing more goods! Here they are!
きた〜！風真いろは 活動二周年記念グッズ 発売決定でござる！
It's here! Kazama Iroha 2nd Anniversary goods release decided!
や本当ね、素晴らしい今回もですね、皆様といろいろ考えた、
Really, they're wonderful this time too. I made them based
あの、意見交換会を参考に作らせていただきましたので
on various ideas from our opinion exchange meetings, so...
ぜひね、一つずつ見ていければと思います。
...I'd like us to look at them one by one.
じゃまず一個目から見ていきましょうか。それではこちら！お、こちらです！
So, let's start with the first one. Here it is! Oh, it's this one!
はい、超美微！二層アクリルパネル！なんと新衣装での飾り物は初めてということで
Yes, super beautiful! 2-layer acrylic panel! This is the first decorative item featuring my new outfit!
もめちゃとってもいい感じですね。
It's really, really nice, isn't it?
イラストはさいね先生に描いていただきました！
The illustration was drawn by Saine-sensei!
めちゃね、すごいんで、この子、超美微って風真が言ってるくらいだから
It's really amazing. Kazama is calling it "super beautiful," so...
ちょっと伝わるかわかんないけど、超美微なのマジで。
...I don't know if it comes across, but it really is super beautiful.
のでぜひね、皆様のおうちに置いていただければなと思います。
So I hope you'll display it in your homes.
はい、そして次のグッズがこちら！
Okay, and the next item is this!
はい！ついにきました！かざま隊証明書発行！イェイ！大変お待たせいたしました。
Yes! It's finally here! Issuing Kazama-tai ID cards! Yay! Sorry to have kept you waiting.
はい、実はですね、皆様から多くリクエストいただいておりました証明書、今回作らせていただきました。
Actually, I've received many requests from everyone for an ID card, so I made it this time.
表にシリアルナンバーが書いてあって、裏には複製のメッセージが書いてあるので
It has a serial number on the front and a printed message on the back.
ぜひね、皆様入手してからのお楽しみということで。
So please look forward to it after you get yours.
名前書くとこあるから、みんな名前ちゃんとマジックペンで書いてね。よろしくお願いします。
There's a place to write your name, so everyone, please write your name with a marker. Please do.
そして皆様もこれをね、入手してかざま隊にならないかっていうね、お誘いでございます。
And this is an invitation for all of you to get this and join the Kazama-tai!
ございますので、ぜひ皆さん買って持ち歩いてくださいね！
So please buy it and carry it around with you!
じゃ、次！
Now, next!
はい！ランダム缶バッジということでですね、今回作らせていただきました。
Yes! We've made these random tin badges this time.
全4種類からランダムで1つお届けでござる！
One will be sent at random from four different types!
通常衣装、お正月衣装、
Standard outfit, New Year outfit,
えっと、新衣装、ポコべとのツーショットの4種類ありますね。
um, the new outfit, and a two-shot with Pokobe. There are four types.
お正月衣装って、実はグッズにするの...
Actually, it's the first time the New Year outfit...
...初めてなんですよ！
...is being made into merchandise!
なのでですね、皆さんコンプ目指してもいいですし、
So, you can aim to complete the set,
あの、買った時に何が届くかウキウキワクワクゴザゴザして...
or enjoy the excitement and 'goza-goza' of what you'll get...
...もらってもいいので、ぜひぜひよろしくお願いします！
...so please check them out!
イラストはですね、いろいろ切り抜きとかもされてる、もちみこ先生に書いていただきました。ありがとうございます！
The illustrations were done by Mochimiko-sensei, who also did various clips. Thank you!
そして次！
And next!
はい、最後はショルダーバッグ！
Yes, the last one is the shoulder bag!
何でショルダーバッグなの？と聞いたそこのあなた！
To those of you asking, "Why a shoulder bag?"
そう、こういうアパレル系もあったらいいなという意見と、
Well, there were opinions that apparel like this would be nice,
なんと今回ですね、こちらのチャックがついて、前面側がビニール、ビニールの仕様になってまして、
and this time, it has a zipper and the front is made of vinyl,
つまりどういうことかって言いますと、あの...
which means...
...痛バッグが作れるショルダーバッグになっております！
...it's a shoulder bag that can be used to make an 'ita-bag'!
痛バが作れます！
You can make an ita-bag!
隊士さんたちの中で、「俺、私、痛バ作ってみたいけどまだ」っていう人がいたら、
If any of you Kazama-tai members want to try making an ita-bag but haven't yet,
ぜひ今回のね、このショルダーバッグ買っていただいて、で一緒に付いてくる、
please buy this shoulder bag,
今回同時販売してる缶バッジとか、証明書とかをね、この中に入れて、
and put the tin badges or ID card sold at the same time inside,
皆さんのオリジナルの痛バッグ、風真いろは痛バッグ作ってくださいね！
to create your own original Kazama Iroha ita-bag!
そして次！
And next!
はい、えー、記念ボイスのご案内でございます。
Yes, this is information about the commemorative voice.
「きみと見たい世界」ということでですね、
It's called "The World I Want to See with You",
今回のライブをモチーフとした、えー、コンセプトのボイスとなっております。
and it's a concept voice themed after this live.
多くは語りません。
I won't say much more.
聞いたものにしかわかりません。
Only those who listen will understand.
今回も一生懸命、血反吐を吐きながら頑張っております。
I worked incredibly hard on this as well, almost coughing up blood.
よろしくお願いいたします！はい、次！
Thank you! Okay, next!
えーっと、そしてフルセットがこちら！
And here is the full set!
こんな感じになっております、豪華でしょ！
It looks like this. It's extravagant, right?
豪華になっております！
It's very extravagant!
そして今回もですね、あるの？という質問が来るかなと思いまして、
And once again, thinking people might ask "Is there one?"
今回数量限定直筆サインあります！
there's a limited-quantity hand-signed version!
はい、箔押しメッセージと限定ボイスが付いてくる数量限定のフルセットと、通常バージョンの2種類あります。
There's a limited-edition full set with a foil-stamped message and limited voice, and a standard version.
このあと21時からなんですけど、ちょっとライブの途中に販売が開始してしまっているかもしれないので、
They go on sale from 21:00, but they might start while the live is still ongoing,
ちょっと押しちゃうかもなんですが、皆さんの配信見ながら数量限定買ってください！
so we might run over, but please buy the limited version while watching the stream!
すいません、お願いします！
Sorry, and thank you!
さて！告知をさせていただきます！
Now! Let me make an announcement!
このあと21時10分頃から、えーっと、押したらもしかしたら変更するかもしれないけど、5分くらい、
From around 21:10 after this—it might change by 5 minutes if we run over—
風真いろは1曲目のオリジナル曲「いろはすてっぷ！」のMVを公開させていただきます！
I will be releasing the MV for my first original song, "Iroha Step!"
こちらです、マジで！
This is it, seriously!
遅くなってごめんね！
Sorry for the wait!
遅くなってごめんね、みんな！
Sorry it took so long, everyone!
お待たせしました！
Thanks for waiting!
もうちょっと、あのですね、いろんな事情がありまして、ちょっと遅くなってしまったんですけど、
Well, due to various circumstances, it got delayed a bit,
この2周年というこのタイミングで出させていただくことができました。
but I was able to release it at this 2nd anniversary timing.
本当にありがとうございます！本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much! Thank you so much!
21時10分から公開予定なんで、プレミア公開、よかったらたくさん聴いてください！
It's scheduled for release at 21:10 as a premiere, so please listen to it a lot!
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you!
ふー、よし！
Phew, okay!
はい、そして、えー、最後の告知になります。
Yes, and this will be the final announcement.
この流れで告知をするのもアレなんですけど、なんとこの度、風真いろは、
It feels a bit much to announce this right after, but this time, Kazama Iroha...
オリジナル曲2曲目ができましたー！
...has a second original song!
曲はこちら！
Here's the song!
はい！「風を仰ぎし麗奈」という曲になっております！
Yes! The song is titled "Kaze wo Aogishi Reina"!
わー、かっこいいでござるな！なんてイケメンなんだろう！
Wow, it's so cool! Such a handsome character!
「いろはすてっぷ！」と比較すると、いい意味で「誰だお前」ってなる感じのオリジナル曲になっていまして、
Compared to "Iroha Step!", it's an original song that makes you go "Who is this?" in a good way.
風真の心の中の葛藤、強くなりたいという気持ちを歌詞にしてもらった曲になっております。
The lyrics reflect the conflict in Kazama's heart and the desire to become stronger.
こちらですね、作曲、ゆうのすけ様にしていただきました。本当にありがとうございます！
The composition was done by Yunosuke-sama. Thank you very much!
こちらの曲はこのあと24時にリリースされるのと、
This song will be released at midnight today,
このあとのパートで初お披露目させていただきますので、
and I'll be performing it for the first time in the next part,
ダンスと合わせて見てください、よろしくお願いします！
so please watch it along with the dance. Thank you!
はい、もう一回お水を飲みます。
Okay, I'll drink some water again.
飲んだ！よし。
I drank it! Okay.
ふー、というわけでですね、皆さん、今紹介させていただきました、
Phew, so everyone, as I just introduced,
「風を仰ぎし麗奈」、早速ですが、
"Kaze wo Aogishi Reina"... without further ado,
ダンス付きでオリ曲初披露させていただきます！
I'll be performing my original song for the first time with a dance!
それでは聴いてください。
Now, please listen.
「風を仰ぎし麗奈」。
"Kaze wo Aogishi Reina".
心寄せてほのか歌う
Drawing my heart close, I sing faintly
花の
Of a flower
唄う様になりたい
I want to become like a song
色づくその前より
Even before I take on color
しっかり
Firmly
地に立ちたい
I want to stand on the ground
唇を芽吹かせる
I'll let my lips bud
やらずの雨が降ろうと
Even if the staying rain falls
惰性に時を啜ることもなく
Without sipping time in inertia
よろずの声を灯せば
If I light up myriad voices
由縁もありし日の記憶にできるから
Because I can turn them into memories of days with a connection
涙ぐむ一縷の風が
A wisp of tearful wind
吹く
blows
後は散らなきゃ愛されないと
Saying that I won't be loved unless I scatter afterwards
幾多の花に肖ること
Emulating countless flowers
比べられようか
Can they be compared?
峠を劈くぐらい
Enough to split a mountain pass
身を切るぐらいに凪を打つ
Enough to cut through me, I strike a calm
有り明けの先で
Beyond the dawn
心寄せてほのか歌う
Drawing my heart close, I sing faintly
悠久に遥か忍ぶ
Enduring for an eternity, far away
一滴の雫を
Continuing to let fall
垂らし続ける
a single drop
清水のごとく
Like pure water
頑丈で剛情な心臓でも
Even with a sturdy and stubborn heart
沸き溶かす思考に
In thoughts that melt and boil
春の起こした妖精は
The fairy awakened by spring
旋律の端を揺らし誘なう
Shakes the edge of the melody and invites me
野道を進む規則で
By the rules of walking the field path
歪む心もなく自分を見出して
Finding myself without a distorted heart
無限城に頂く風よ
Oh wind received at the Infinite Castle
差し向かえ
Blow this way
心寄せてほのか歌う
Drawing my heart close, I sing faintly
止まらず澄み渡る川の果ては
If the end of the unstopping, clear river
空ならば
Is the sky
赴くがままに風を仰ぎ
Gazing at the wind as I go
垢抜けてまだ麗ならは
If I'm refined and still beautiful
直向きな姿に追い風を
A tailwind for my earnest figure
後は散らなきゃ愛されないと
Saying that I won't be loved unless I scatter afterwards
幾多の花に肖ること
Emulating countless flowers
比べられようか
Can they be compared?
峠を劈くぐらい
Enough to split a mountain pass
身を切るぐらいに凪を打つ
Enough to cut through me, I strike a calm
有り明けの先で
Beyond the dawn
心寄せてほのか歌う
Drawing my heart close, I sing faintly
悠久に遥か忍ぶ
Enduring for an eternity, far away
金色の髪がなびく
My golden hair flutters
いろはの新しいオリジナル曲、聴いてくれてありがとうございました！
Thank you for listening to my new original song!
楽しい時間はあっという間！次の曲が最後の曲です！
Fun times go by in a flash! The next song is the last one!
全力で最後まで楽しんでってねー！
Enjoy yourselves to the fullest until the very end!
ごめん
Sorry
憧れてた
I looked up to you
追いかけてた
I was chasing after you
いつまでもそばにいたかった
I wanted to stay by your side forever
完璧なあなた
You, who were perfect
嫌になった
I grew sick of it
同じように
In the same way
愛をもらって育ったのに
Though we were both raised receiving love
いつからか差が開いてた
At some point, a gap opened up between us
八つ当たりだって
Even taking it out on you
したかったねえ baby
Is something I wanted to do, baby
神様を信じなさ過ぎた
I didn't believe in God enough
強くなれよと
Telling me to "become strong"
うざい平等なんて嘘つき
This annoying "equality" is a lie
分かってるけど
I know that, but...
可愛いとか もてたいとか
Wanting to be cute, wanting to be popular
諦めたいの女の子だし
I want to give up on those, after all I'm a girl
自分らしく 猫被り
In my own way, feigning innocence
オンリーワンだよ
I'm the only one
愛してね 生き様は無限にある
Please love me; there are infinite ways of living
お父さんの大袈裟な言葉
My father's exaggerated words
自分らしく
In my own way
猫被り
Feigning innocence
私らしく行こう
I'll go my own way
暇じゃない人生生きよう
Let's live a life that's not boring
さて 理想を言えばキリがなくて
Well, there's no end to ideals
無い物全部欲しがって
Wanting everything I don't have
鏡を見たって ため息
I look in the mirror and sigh
はぁ
Haa
あなただって 悩んでいた
You were worried too
知らなかった
I didn't know
みんなと同じだと知った
I found out we're all the same
ピンと張った糸
The tight string
緩んでいく 止め処ない
Starts to loosen endlessly
神様は楽しんでいる 予測できない
God is enjoying this unpredictable
一歩
Step
私はそれ以上に
I'm going to
楽しんでやるぜ
Enjoy it even more
勉強とか お仕事とか
On studies or work
諦めない 女の子だし
I won't give up, because I'm a girl
元気よく 愛想良く
Energetic and friendly
たまには空回り
Though sometimes I spin my wheels
ついてきて
Follow me
愛した分 愛されるの
I'm loved as much as I love
お母さんがくれたアドバイス
Advice my mother gave me
弾けて ミックスしても
Even if I pop and mix it up
私らしく行こう
I'll go my own way
胸張って生きる
Living with my head held high
さらけ出せば 心が温められていたんだ
When I laid myself bare, my heart was warmed
好きにいていい
It's okay to stay as you like
痛くない
It doesn't hurt
神様は夢与えた 変われるために
God gave me a dream so that I could change
散々 乗っかってやるよ
I'm going to ride this all the way
最後まで付き合ってもらうよ
I'll have you stay with me until the end
雨は止んで 傘を閉じた
The rain stopped, I closed my umbrella
今まで見えてなかった景色
Seeing sights I couldn't see before
透明が反射して
The transparency reflected
世界を照らした
And lit up the world
胸踊る
My heart races
可愛いとか モテたいとか
Being cute or wanting to be popular
諦めない 女の子だし
I won't give up, because I'm a girl
自分らしく 猫被り
In my own way, feigning innocence
ナンバーワンでしょ
I'm number one, right?
愛してね 生き様は無限にある
Please love me; there are infinite ways of living
お父さんの大袈裟な言葉
My father's exaggerated words
自分らしく 猫被り
In my own way, feigning innocence
私らしく行こう
I'll go my own way
暇じゃない人生生きよう
Let's live a life that's not boring
皆様！今日は来てくれてありがとうございました！
Everyone! Thank you for coming today!
最高の2周年ライブになりました！
It was the best 2nd anniversary live!
本当にありがとう！
Thank you so much!
バイバイでござるー！
Bye-bye de gozaru~!
本日は風真いろは2周年ライブにお越しいただきまして、誠にありがとうございました。
Thank you very much for coming to Kazama Iroha's 2nd anniversary live today.
本公演の感想と実況は、ハッシュタグ「#風真いろは2周年LIVE」でたくさん呟いてくださいね！
Please tweet your thoughts and commentary on this concert using the hashtag #KazamaIroha2ndAnniversaryLIVE!
それではまた、メン限でお会いしましょう。
Well then, see you again at the members-only stream.
あ、プレミア公開もよろしく！じゃーね！バイバーイ！
Oh, and please check out the premiere too! See ya! Bye-bye!